That's learn about multi-dimensional and multidimensional array is an array of areas.
Each element of a multidimensional array is an array itself.
What does this mean?
For example.
We have int double angle the brackets, a equal new and three and four.
The multidimensional array name is a.
So at this case, we have the first step declaring a two dimension dimensional array called a how many
number or a number of pairs of of angular brackets.
There are two.
So it is two dimensional array.
You can create three dimensional fourth dimension and so on.
But the main concepts of the main concept and the main usage of arrays is the single array and single
multi single dimensional array and multidimensional array, which is two dimensional array.
The second step is new, a new and three and four, we are instantiating an array of city heroes and
four cars.
And this is the array we are making at row one row to end row three and column one, column two, columns
three and column four.
So this declaration and a equal new and and we have zero equals three and the four equals the the number
of columns.
OK, so the first number indicate the number of rows and the second number indicate the number of columns.
And this these are the representation of the indices of the elements.
So index, the first index at throw one and column one is a f zero and zero there row one, column two
is zero and a +1.
OK.
And so on.
This is very important about the multidimensional array, please write it down in order to understand
this functional know how to create to the rise in sea, we create and array a RR or any name.
We put in the first angle to bracket the number of rows and the second number is in the angled bracket,
indicating the number of columns.
So we put the first array and the second array, the first array containing one two, three four and
five six seven eight as the second array.
Remember, through the array as array of arrays and Java, we put into early.
This is.
Multi-dimensional array, and we have one, two, three, four and five, six, seven and they sort
of there it was a mistake.
So and double angle brackets and the array, the first array and the second array in Python, we have
to declare directly to like an array and multidimensional array and inside angled brackets.
There is the the value of the two arrays, so we directly implement that to arrays.
This would result in creating a multi-dimensional array and just like think about it as a matrix.
So it is a grid and contains that numbers one two three four at the first row and five, six, seven
and eight in the second row.
This is how we implement and how to create a 2D array.
Now creating two the array with different size, you can create a multidimensional array with different
sizes.
So I have this array.
A contains the first array with three elements.
The second array with the fourth four elements and the third.
Array with one element.
This is how we've created this look.
So this code will looks like this, and if we need to calculate the length of each row, we are going
to make system without that brand.
And we use a at index zero length.
So a at index zero, we are specifying that the row at index zero, so it's the first row that length.
Here we how to get the length of Arrow.
It's very important to point just if you have a 2D array.
If you specify only one index cell we are representing, we are talking about true.
If we are specifying that two and this is we are talking about a cell.
OK.
So when you see when you need a length of rope, use a of index of the row that you are going to get.